# Pratik Pingale

Pune. India

🖫 +919075715518 | @ pratikbpingale9075@gmail.com | 💣 proxzima.dev | 🗘 github.com/PROxZIMA | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/pratik-pingale

## Personal Profile

I seek problems to solve them. I Love to learn whatever that will make the future. Highly versatile and adapt quickly to a changing environment. Passionate, and specialized in Front-End Web Development alongside modern frameworks like React/Django and other libraries. Open Source contributor and Competitive Programmer.

## Professional Experience

Convin.ai Pune, India

Backend Engineer and Android Developer

Sept 2021 - Apr 2022

- Collaborated with a thirteen-person team to develop and integrate backend APIs using Django Rest Framework which improved
  and optimized data handling.
- Analyzed and performed speech-to-text conversion on customer call recording audios using Amazon Transcribe and Google Translate APIs along with AI based filters to recognize multilingual parts of speech.
- Build and deployed an organizational-level Android application with advanced functionalities like call recording and efficient background syncing for large audio files which aided a big management team of a renowned organization.
- Letter Of Recommendation ♂.
- Technical Skills: Python, Django REST framework, Android, Kotlin, AWS, PostgreSQL, Ubuntu Linux, Scripting, Git.
- Soft Skills: Teamwork, Time Management, Communication, and Presentation skills.

# Organizational Experience\_\_\_\_\_

AISSMS COE Pune, India

Core Team Member Google Developer Student Club

Sept 2020 - Sept 2022

- · Team leader of the Competitive Programming Team. Conducted many virtual and physical events for freshers and juniors.
- The events were based on Git, Data Structures, Algorithms, and Competitive Programming which helped them to understand the basic fundamentals and eventually get better at coding.
- Member of the Web Development Team. Contributed to the DSC AISSMSCOE © official website.
- · Technical Skills: Python with Algorithms, Data Structures, Tailwind CSS, Firebase, Git.
- · Soft Skills: Leadership, Time Management, Communication, Logical Thinking.

AISSMS COE Pune, India

Core Team Member Microsoft Student Club

July 2021 - Sept 2022

- Build a University Timetable Scheduler 2 model with a colleague, that works using a Genetic algorithm and is portable for scheduling scenarios may it be a schedule for school, employee timesheet, etc.
- Designed to be flexible to any case with low time complexity compared to the existing models which were only useful in specific scenarios.
- Build a Certificate App C? for easier certificate generation and distribution. This helped the college's Sports department to handle competitions and events related certificates.
- Technical Skills: Python with Genetic Algorithms, Django, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, CI & CD, Git.
- Soft Skills: Teamwork, Time Management, Communication, Logical Thinking.

## Projects\_\_\_\_\_

DarkSpider ♂ Pune, India

AISSMS COE

AISSMS COE

Aug 2022 - Current

Sept 2021 - Jan 2022

- Identification of Network Structures of the Dark Web by Exploring its Topological Properties by crawling and extracting onion web pages via the TOR Dark web network using a multi-threaded BFS crawler.
- · DarkSpider is a multi-threaded crawler and extractor for regular or onion web pages through the TOR network, written in Python.
- Technical Skills: Python with multi-threaded BFS crawler, TOR.
- Soft Skills: Presentation skills, Leadership, Teamwork, Logical Thinking.

Timetable Scheduler ♂ Pune, India

• An intelligent timetable generator that generates a University timetable using a Genetic Algorithm.

- An intengent uniterable generator that generates a University uniterable using a Genetic Agorithm.
- · The project uses Genetic Algorithm to satisfy the Hard & Soft constraints related to the Timetable schedule.
- Technical Skills: Python with Genetic Algorithms, Django.
- Soft Skills: Time Management, Teamwork, Presentation skills, Logical Thinking.

Museum Gallery ☐ Pune, India

Personal Project May 2020 - Aug 2020

- A VR based Museum application made for enjoying museums from home.
- Technical Skills: Android with Java, Google VR SDK.

#### **Twitter Sentiment Analysis** □

Pune, India

Apr 2022 - May 2022

Personal Project

• Twitter Sentiment analysis of tweets using vaderSentiment, CountVectorizer, and KMeans.

- · Analyzing and cleaning texts using stop words removal, tokenization, stemming, and lemmatization.
- The least of the state using stop words removal, tokenization, steinming, and remind

• Technical Skills: Python with KMeans, Pandas, NumPy, seaborn, scikit-learn.

Pune, India

**proxzima.dev** ♂ Personal Project

May 2022 - Current

- · Highly customizable, easy-to-use, and minimal terminal styled website, powered by Next.js.
- · Technical Skills: TypeScript with React.js and Next.js, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and Shell Scripting.

## **Education**

#### **AISSMS College of Engineering**

Pune, India

**B-Tech in Computer Engineering** 

Aug 2019 - Current

· Organizing and managing technical events.

9.38 SGPA

- Courses: Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Natural Language Processing, Blockchain Technology, Computer and Security, Database Management Systems, Data Structures and Algorithms, Computer Graphics, Discrete Mathematics
- Honours: Artificial Intelligence for Big Data Analytics, Machine Learning & Data Science, Statistics and Machine Learning, Data Science and Visualization

#### **Pragnya Junior College**

Pune, India

High School

Jul 2017 - May 2019

- · Passed with Distinction
- · Specialised in Physics, Chemistry, and Maths with Computer Science

### **Skills**

**Programming** Python (Numpy, Pandas, Jupyter, Django, Flask. etc.), C/C++, Kotlin, HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript,

TypeScript(React.js), MySQL, PostgreSQL.

Miscellaneous Linux, Shell (Bash/Zsh), ŁTĘX(Overleaf), Figma, Postman, Google Cloud, Firebase, Git.

**Soft Skills** Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Versatility, Adaptability, Multitasking, and Public Speaking.

## **Achievements**

2020 **Winner**, Internal Hackathon for Smart India Hackathon (SIH)

2015 **Winner**, District level Karate Competition

India

#### Interests\_

**Linux** Since 2020, I have been in love with Linux. Linux ricing  $\[ \]$  is my hobby.

**Anime** I enjoy watching anime of a few specific genres like shonen and seinen.

Video Games I always had the gaming gene. I mostly play on my phone and occasionally on my PS3.

**Karate** I started karate when I was 15. I have participated in a few state and national-level competitions. **Music** I enjoy almost all types of music but the genres I enjoy the most are aesthetic EDMs and electro.

### **Languages**.

**English** Professional proficiency

Hindi Native proficiency

Marathi Bilingual proficiency